Guide to the William C. Lynch Dennis Brain Collection ARS.0138
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Compact Discs, circa 1936-2011; 155 discs 123 CD-Rs; 32 compact discs
  - Non-commerical recordings, circa 1936-2011; 117 items 113 CD-Rs; 4 compact discs
    - Moeran, Franck, Delius, Bax, Rimsky-Korsakov, and Borodin, 1947-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 113)
      Moeran, E. J. (Ernest John), 1894-1950. Sinfonietta. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Royal Albert Hall (London, England). 1947 April 26. Private recording, unpublished.
      Franck, César, 1822-1890. Chasseur maudit. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Kingsway Hall. 1951 March 9.
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Messe des Lebens, prelude part 2. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1948 May 8.
      Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. Garden of Fand. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 December 14-15.
      Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Ispanskoe kaprichchio. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1955 March 16-17.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Quartets, strings, no. 2, D major. Notturno; arr. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1956 July 27.
    - Mozart, Berlioz, Mendelssohn, Borodin, and Strauss (Richard), 1947-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 114)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Symphonies, K. 338, C major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Klemperer, Otto, 1885-1973, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1955 November 24.
      Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Roi Lear. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 September 10 and 1947 November 11.
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Octet, violins (4), violas, violoncellos, op. 20, E♭major. Scherzo; arr. Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 December 8.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Polovet︠s︡kiĭ marsh. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1953 February 13.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Feuersnot. Liebesszene. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 April 11.
    - Borodin, 1953-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 115)
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Uverti︠u︡ra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1956 February 8.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Polovet︠s︡kai︠a︡ pli︠a︡ska. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1953 January 21.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 3, A minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 September 24.
    - Delius, Strauss (Richard), and Wagner, 1947-1951; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 116)
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Over the hills and far away. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1951 January 19.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Bürger als Edelmann. Suite. Selections. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 November 5.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Rheingold. Einzug der Götter in Walhall. Schöffler, Paul, 1897-1977, bass. Jones, Parry, tenor. Evans, Nancy, 1915-2000, mezzo-soprano. Chitty, George, tenor. Field-Hyde, Margaret, soprano. Garside, Gwladys, soprano. Furmedge, Edith, mezzo-soprano. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. EMI unissued recording. 1947 September 22.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Intermezzo (Opera). Entr'acte. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Theatre Royal, Drury Lane (London England). Live broadcast. 1947 October 12.
    - Berlioz, Haydn, Glinka, Ippolitov-Ivanov, and Arnold, 1948-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 117)
      Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Harold en Italie. Excerpt. Primrose, William, 1904-1982, viola. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961. 1951 November 15.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 80, D minor. Third and fourth movements only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Pritchard, John, 1921-1989, conductor. 1954 December 20-21.
      Glinka, Mikhail Ivanovich, 1804-1857. Valse-fantaisie. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1948 November 8.
      Ippolitov-Ivanov, Mikhail Mikhaĭlovich, 1859-1935. Kavkazskie ėskizy. Excerpts from sketches 1,3, and 4. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1953 June 23 and 1953 June 16.
      Arnold, Malcolm. Scottish dances. Three out of four only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Irving, Robert, 1913-1991, conductor. 1957 June 18.
    - Schoeck, Bach, and Humperdinck, 1953-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 118)
      Schoeck, Othmar, 1886-1957. Concertos, horn, string orchestra, op. 65. Sacher Orchestra; Sacher, Paul, 1906-1999, conductor. Radio Suisse romande. Live recording. 1956 May 4.
      Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Brandenburgische Konzerte. Nr. 1. Hurwitz, Emanuel, 1919-2006, viola. Goossens, Leon, 1897-1988, oboe. Sanders, Neill, horn. Boyd Neel Orchestra; Neel, Boyd, conductor. 1956 July 26.
      Humperdinck, Engelbert, 1854-1921. Hänsel und Gretel. Vorspiel. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Karajan, Herbert von, conductor. 1953 June 27.
    - Handel and Mozart, 1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 119)
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Water music. Orchestrated by Harty, Hamilton, Sir, 1879-1941. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1952 July 31.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 287, B♭ major. Movements 1-5. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1952 May 2.
    - Milhaud, Mozart, and Beethoven, 1955 June 22; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 120)
      Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Cheminée du roi René. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. 1955 June 22.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Arranged for oboe, flute, clarinet, horn, bassoon, and piano. Malcolm, George, 1917-1997, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. 1955 June 22.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Britten, Benjamin 1913-1976, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. 1955 June 22.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Hansen, Conrad, piano. 1950 April 20.
    - Ferguson, Berkeley, Dukas, Schumann, and Schubert, 1943-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 121)
      Ferguson, Howard, 1908-1999. Octet, woodwinds, horn, strings, op. 4. Griller String Quartet. Juler, Pauline, clarinet. Merrett, James Edward, double bass. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. O'Brien, Jack, violin. Griller, Sidney, violin. Burton, Phillips, viola. Hampton, Colin, 1911-1996, cello. 1943 May 6 and 1943 May 24.
      Berkeley, Lennox, 1903-1989. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 44. Horsley, Colin, piano. Rostal, Max, violin. British Broadcasting Corporation broadcast. 1956 January 9.
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Britten, Benjamin 1913-1976, piano. Holland Festival. 1956 July 6.
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Adagio und Allegro, horn, piano, op. 70, A♭major. Britten, Benjamin 1913-1976, piano. Holland Festival. 1956 July 6.
      Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Auf dem Strom. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. Holland Festival. 1956 July 6.
    - Bowen, Kaminski, Lewis, and Schreiter, 1950-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 122)
      Bowen, York, 1884-1961. Concertos, horn, string orchestra, op. 150. Welbeck Orchestra; Miles, Maurice, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation broadcast. 1956 July 1.
      Kaminski, Heinrich, 1886-1946. Ballade for horn and piano. Billing, Klaus, piano. 1950 September 18.
      Lewis, Anthony, 1915-1983. Concerto for Horn and Strings. BBC Midland Light Orchestra; Gentry, Gerald, 1927-, conductor. 1957 January 18.
      Schreiter, Heinz. Sonatina for horn and piano op.12. Norddeutscher Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Westphal, Alfred, conductor. 1954 May 6.
    - Dukas, Schumann, Tomlinson, Fricker, Seiber, and Mozart, 1953-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 123)
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Billing, Klaus, piano. RIAS-Symphonie-Orchester. Live broadcast. 1953 May 4.
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Adagio und Allegro, horn, piano, op. 70, A♭major. Billing, Klaus, piano. RIAS-Symphonie-Orchester. Live broadcast. 1953 May 4.
      Tomlinson, Ernest, 1924-. Rhapsody and Rondo for Horn and Orchestra. BBC Concert Orchestra; Tomlinson, Ernest, 1924-, conductor. BBC Light Programme. 1953 May 4.
      Fricker, Peter Racine, 1920-1990. Quintet, winds, op. 5. Dennis Brain Ensemble. Edinburgh International Festival. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1957 August 24.
      Seiber, Mátyás, 1905-1960. Phantasies, flute, horn, strings. Allegri String Quartet. Morris, Gareth, flute. Recorded 1957 February 3. Broadcast 1957 February 6.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Norddeutscher Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Schmidt-Isserstedt, Hans, 1900-1973, conductor.
    - Britten, Mussorgsky, Strauss (Richard), Mendelssohn, Wagner, and Haydn., 1947-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 124)
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Young person’s guide to the orchestra. Excerpts. Pears, Peter, Sir, narrator. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Markevitch, Igor, 1912-1983, conductor. 1952 September 11, 1952 September 13, 1954 June 8.
      Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Kartinki s vystavki; arr. Horn solo passage only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1955 October 11-12, 1956 June 18.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Heldenleben. Horn solo and concluding section only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 October 21, 1947 October 28, 1947 October 29, 1947 December 14.
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Sommernachtstraum. Notturno. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kubelík, Rafael, 1914-1996, conductor. 1952, February 16.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Fliegende Holländer. Ouvertüre. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor.1954 April 16.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 31, D major. Movements 1, 2 and 4 only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Westrup, J. A. (Jack Allan), 1904-1975, conductor.
    - Wagner, Haydn, Rimsky-Korsakov, Kodaly, Borodin, Tchaikovsky, and Liszt., 1944-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 125)
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1952 December 21.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Liebestod. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1952 December 21.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Notturno No.5 in C-minor. Geiringer, Karl, 1899-1989, arranger. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Pritchard, John, 1921-1989, conductor. 1954 December 21.
      Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Maĭskai︠a︡ nochʹ. Uverti︠u︡ra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1951 August 30-31.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Uverti︠u︡ra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1956 February 17-18.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Horn solo only. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. 1944 June 8.
      Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Préludes. Excerpts. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1952 November 10.
      Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Mazeppa (Symphonic poem). Horn solo only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1952 November 10.
    - Hindemith, Haydn, and Handel, 1948-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 126)
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Sonatas, horns (4). Sanders, Neill, horn. Cursue, Alfred, horn. Chapman, Edmund, horn. 1956 January 5.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 40, F major. Beers, Ian, horn. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1948 March 20.
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Operas. Selections; arr. Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, arranger. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1951 March 16 and 1951 April 3.
    - Strauss (Richard) and Mozart, 1951-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 127)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. WDR Rundfunkorchester Köln, Wand, Günter, 1912-2002, conductor. Live broadcast, Cologne. 1951 January 23.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert. conductor. Royal Festival Hall (London, England). 1956 June 20.
    - Mozart, Haydn, Kay, and Bach., 1952-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 128)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 388, C minor. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1952 June 23-24.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimenti, H. II, 7, C major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 September 24.
      Kay, Norman, 1929-2001. Miniature quartet. Adeney, Richard, flute. Waters, Stephen, clarinet. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1957 May 18.
      Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel, 1714-1788. Concertos, harpsichord, piano, orchestra, H. 479, E♭ major. Last movement only. Malcolm, George, 1917-1997, Harpsichord. Lionel Slater, piano forte. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1953 March 23-24.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Marsch für den Prinzen von Wales. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1949 December 28.
    - Mozart and Haydn, circa 1946-1951; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 129)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 166, E♭ major. London Wind Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1946 September 27.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 375, E♭ major. Minuet I and Trio. London Wind Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimenti, H. II, 46, B♭ major. Chorale St. Antoni. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1951 January 19. Dennis Brain participation uncertain.
    - Berlioz, (Bayeux Tapestry), Borodin, Beethoven, 1944-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 130)
      Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Troyens. Chasse royale et orage. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme. 1947 July 2.
      Bayeux tapestry. Incidental music for British Broadcasting Corporation Children's Hour. Theme Music and Hunting Scene. Robertson, Alec, arranger. British Broadcasting Corporation, broadcast. 1944 September 28.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Uverti︠u︡ra. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Dobrowen, Issay, 1893-1953, conductor. 1949 May 16 and 1949 May 26-28.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814). Komm, Hoffnung. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 September 20.
      Bayeux tapestry. Incidental music for British Broadcasting Corporation Children's Hour. Excerpt. 1944 September 20. Sir Thomas Beecham Society (Great Britain) talk by Brymer, Jack. 1975 September 26. Talk discusses a Royal Festival Hall concert from 1956 with Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961 conducting the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra in Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Daphnis et Chloé.
    - Rawsthorne and Haydn, 1948; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 131)
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 101, D major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme. 1948.
      Rawsthorne, Alan, 1905-1971. Cortèges. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme. 1948.
    - Brahms, 1952 September 29; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 132)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957, conductor. 1952 September 29.
    - Brahms, Handel, and Offenbach, circa 1947-1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 133)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Symphonies, no. 3, op. 90, F major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957, conductor.
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Amaryllis suite. Gavotte. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1952 October 1.
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Amaryllis suite. Scherzo. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1952 October 1.
      Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Tavern scene; excerpt from 1951 film The Tales of Hoffman. Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, arranger. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Recorded 1947.
    - Rossini, Smetana, and Respighi, 1950-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 134)
      Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Cambiale di matrimonio. Sinfonia. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1950 September 28.
      Smetana, Bedřich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevěsta. Ouvertura. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1953 June 24.
      Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Fontane di Roma. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1955 March 18-19.
    - Brahms, Liszt, and Borodin, 1948-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 135)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Last movement excerpt. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 May 5,7 and 1954 July 26,28,31.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 15, D minor. Excerpts from the first and last movements. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kubelík, Rafael, 1914-1996, conductor. 1952 September 3-5.
      Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Fantasie über ungarische Volksmelodien. Selections. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1948 April 27. Radio Feature. British Broadcasting Corporation broadcast. Musical excerpts and reminiscences. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Introduction by Burton, Humphrey, 1931-. 1957 January.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Uverti︠u︡ra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Dobrowen, Issay, 1893-1953, conductor. 1949 May 18, 26-28.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. V sredneĭ Azii. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951, conductor. 1946 January 24.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Traditional arrangement. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Mackerras, Charles, 1925-2010, conductor. 1957 June 1.
    - Mozart, Mascagni, Tchaikovsky, and Bruckner, 1948-1954; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 136)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Così fan tutte. Per pietà, ben mio. Glyndebourne Festival Orchestra; Busch, Fritz, 1890-1951, conductor. Rehearsal recording. 1950 July 12.
      Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Intermezzo. Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, organ. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 July 24.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Evgeniĭ Onegin. St︠s︡ena pisʹma. Excerpt. Welitsch, Ljuba, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1948 May 22.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Capriccio italien. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 23 (Edmund Chapman, first horn) and 1953 January 24 (Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, first horn).
      Bruckner, Anton, 1824-1896. Symphonies, no. 4, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Matačić, Lovro von, conductor. 1954 December 11,13 and 14.
    - Brahms, 1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 137)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 2, op. 73, D major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1952 September 29.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Tragische Ouvertüre. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1952 October 1.
    - Sibelius and Borodin, 1952-1953; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 138)
      Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Tapiola. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1953 July 14-15.
      Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Finlandia. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor.1952 July 29-31.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. V sredneĭ Azii. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Collingwood, Lawrance, conductor. 1953 March 9.
    - Dvorak, Mendelssohn, and Saint-Saens, 1947; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 139)
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Zlatý kolovrat. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 September 15, 1947 November 6, and 1947 November 29.
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Märchen von der schönen Melusine. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 September 11, 1947 November 11, and 1947 November 27.
      Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Rouet d'Omphale. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 April 22.
    - Britten, 1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 140)
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Canticle, no. 3. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, piano. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. Holland Festival. Nederlandse Omroep Stichting, live broadcast. 1956 July 6.
      Sir Thomas Beecham Society (Great Britain). Talk by Brymer, Jack entitled "On the Subject of a Royal Festival Hall Concert". Includes Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1956.
    - Various radio specials relating to Brain, 1988-1996; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 141)
      Music Machine. Thompson, Michael, presenter. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1995 May 21. Dennis Brain 80th Birthday. Morris, Gareth, presenter. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1996 May 17. EMI Testament. Osborne, Richard, 1943-, presenter. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1995 March 11. Kaleidoscope. British Broadcasting Corporation. Berkeley, Michael, presenter. 1988.
    - Various radio specials relating to Brain, 1998-1991; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 142)